Leslie Ernenwein papers, 1937-1962
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Papers of Leslie Ernenwein, 1937-1962
AZ 295
Ernenwein, Leslie
This collection includes correspondence, clippings, photographs, background material, notes, typescripts, published articles, and galleys concerning cowboys and the West. Correspondents are publishers and agents. It includes background material for stories about Death Valley, Imperial Valley, and Yuma Prison; and photographs of Yuma Prison and cattle branding.
1.7 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Leslie Ernenwein was an author of Western stories and a feature writer of the Tucson Daily Citizen.
Organization
This collection is organized into three series:
Series I: Correspondence, 1937-1962
Series II: Writings, ca. 1937-1957
Series III: Background Material, Notes Galleys and Clippings
Scope and Content Note
This collection includes correspondence, clippings, photographs, background material, notes, typescripts, published articles, and galleys concerning cowboys and the West. Correspondents are publishers and agents. It includes background material for stories about Death Valley, Imperial Valley, and Yuma Prison; and photographs of Yuma Prison and cattle branding.
Access Terms
Journalists -- Arizona
Western stories
Correspondence
Manuscripts
Photographs
Separated Material
Books received with the collection were removed and cataloged separately.
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence, 1937-1962
  - Correspondence: Publishers, popular publications. 1937-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Publishers, Street & Smith. 1939-1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Publishers, Phoenix Press. 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Publishers, Dutton. 1944-1950 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Publishers, Standard Magazines, Inc. 1944-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Publishers, Best Publications, Popular Library. 1950-1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Publishers, Alan Swallow and Sage Books. 1947-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Publishers, Argosy. 1943-1948 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Publishers, Curtis Brown, Ltd. 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Publishers, Ranch Romances. 1942-1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Publishers, Robert McBride & Co. 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Publishers and miscellaneous. 1938-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Agents, Lurton Blassingame. 1940-1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Agents, Joseph Shaw of S. A. Sanders. 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Fan Mail. 1940-1957 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: Writings, ca. 1937-1957
  - Articles and Stories (typescripts). (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Includes:
    "The Battle Custer Won"
    "Nick the Meek"
    "Shiftless Slow"
    "Trail Boss"
    "Weaving a Better Blanket"
    "Cow Country Quiz" (a series)
  - List of Articles and Stories in Publications. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series III: Background Material, Notes Galleys and Clippings
  - Background material and notes on Death Valley and 20-Mule Team. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Background material and notes on Imperial Valley. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Background material and notes on Yuma Prison. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cattle Branding Photographs. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Bunkhouse Material." (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Outline, notes drafts for Hell Bent, published as Bullet Barricade. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Two notebooks of "references." (Box 2)
  - Published stories, articles and book reviews. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Leads" for stories and articles. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Clippings. 1957-1962 (Box 3, Folder 3-7)
  - Galley: Bullet Barricade. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Galley: Give a Man a Gun. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Galley: Gun Hawk. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Galley: High Gun. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Galley: The Texas Gun. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook of clippings. (Volume 4)